sketchmob.com 2014-11-28

# Privacy Policy | Sketchmob

* * *

##### **Registration**

We do not require registration in order to browse on our site. You may choose to give us your contact information during registration or at other times. We then may use that information to contact you about the products and services on our site for which you have expressed interest. Registration is required to use certain interactive features such as reviewing products, saving designs, and placing orders. We offer the ability to access Sketchmob by logging in with or connecting via a third party social network or email service,, including but not limited to Facebook or Facebook Connect (“Third Party Platforms”). If you access the Website via a Third Party Platform we will access and store the information explicitly allowed by the social network platform by their Terms of Service or otherwise, once you allow us to do so, through an interface provided by the social network platform. As we do not have control over the user interface provided by social network platforms, we do not take any responsibility for any changes or problems with the interface or exchange of information provided by any of these social network platforms.

By accessing Sketchmob via a Third Party Platform, you grant Sketchmob permission to contact you at the email address associated with your account associated with the Third Party Platform. Members of Sketchmob’s marketing lists will occasionally receive information on products, services, special sales, and our newsletter. You have the option to opt out from receiving these types of information, and you may unsubscribe at any time by changing the settings in your account profile. Registration allows customers to utilize ‘print art’ functionality on the website. Users can customize an unlimited number of products. The text on these saved designs may contain personal information including addresses, contact information or dates of personal events. This information is only available to the registered user and Sketchmob staff. The customer also has the ability to ‘share their art.’ This is available so that a customer can allow other people to view or comment on their saved stationery designs. Sketchmob will provide a link to the invitee to view the saved stationery. Saved art are not publicly available. The customer may also explicitly choose to share an art on a social network or other publishing mechanism. Any art or personal information shared on third party services are subject to that service’s Terms and Privacy Policy.

##### **  
Information Collected**

We collect personal information when you register with us and when you use our services. Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number, and that is not otherwise publicly available. When you create a Sketchmob account we ask for information such as your name and email address. When you place an order we ask for a phone number, billing and shipping address, and billing information. By accessing Sketchmob via a Third Party Platform, you authorize Sketchmob to receive certain of your personal information that is available on or through your Third Party Platform account, including, without limitation, your profile information, name, email address, gender, birthday, current city, friends or follower names, your photos, profile picture, privacy settings and certain other information that will be disclosed to you during the login process.  
We do not intentionally target our site or our services to children, and we will not knowingly collect personal information from children without obtaining prior, verifiable parental consent. We may obtain information about children who are named on invitations or other products, or that is otherwise provided by users. If we are informed that a registered user is under the age of 13 and has registered without prior, verifiable parental consent, then we will endeavor to remove such personal information from our records.

##### **  
Use of Information**

We use your personal information to fulfill your requests for products and services, to improve our services, to customize the advertising and content you see, and to contact you. By creating an account, purchasing or saving a design on Sketchmob.com, you may be opted into receiving email messages. These messages could include changes to features of our service and additional email messages about our products, services, contests, and promotions that we feel may be of interest to you. If you no longer wish to receive these types of promotional communications from us, you may select the unsubscribe link which is present in each email. Opting out may prevent you from receiving email messages regarding special offers, improvements, or other updates. If you use Sketchmob, including accessed via a Third Party Platform, to send information to another person, we may store your personal information, and the personal information provided by you, of any recipient. We may use that other person’s contact information to allow him or her to access the information you requested we send. We use anonymous information, such as that pertaining to web pages viewed, to analyze trends, to track user’s movements, to provide a better website experience and to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We do not use this data in a manner that would identify you personally. Your product reviews, comments and any other information you make available in public areas of our website likely will be seen by people and organizations not related to or controlled by Sketchmob.

##### **  
Information Sharing and Disclosure**

Sketchmob will not rent, sell, or share your personal information with other people or nonaffiliated companies except to provide products or services that you have requested, or unless we have your permission as agreed in this Privacy Policy or otherwise. If you submit a different address for shipping than for billing, the shipping information is only used to ship the package. You may specify an email address for the recipient if you wish for us to send them an email notification ‘gift message.’ The shipping recipient will not be opted in to any marketing distribution lists without their permission. We may share personal information with contractors or trusted service providers who work with us under confidentiality agreements, for example our printers and online proof rendering service need this information in order to fulfill your order. We may also contract with vendors to help us analyze traffic and usage of our site, communicate with you about offers and services from Sketchmob, and to help us provide better services. These companies will not be provided any independent right to use or share personal information. We may share personal information in order to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. We also may share personal information when we believe it necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law. In addition, we may transfer information about you if we are acquired by, reorganized or merged with another company. In that event, we will notify active registered users if there is a need to change this Privacy Policy.

##### **  
Cookies**

A cookie is a small data file that we download to your computer, containing information about you to facilitate interaction with our site and services. Cookies make it possible for us to store contents of your shopping cart until you are ready to check out, and to recognize your browser when you visit. By doing this, we can personalize your visits and save you time during checkout. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. If you reject the cookie, you may still use our site. However, in order to enjoy the benefits of being a registered user, your browser must be set to accept cookies.

##### **  
Security**

When our registration or order forms ask you to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted for transmission. When you provide information via these forms, we use SSL encryption and this should be indicated by a ‘lock’ icon in web browsers such Microsoft Internet Explorer and Mozilla Firefox.

##### **  
Users from Outside the USA**

Our service is offered in accord with the law of California within the United States. If you are accessing our site from any jurisdiction with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure that differ from applicable California or United States law, then you consent via your continued use of our service to transferring your Personal Information into the United States.

##### **  
Third Party Sites**

Our Websites may contain links to or features from other websites. Our Privacy Policy only applies to the Sketchmob websites and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other websites. You should check the privacy policies of those sites before providing your personal information to them.

© 2014 Sketchmob LLC, – All Rights Reserved. Last updated: September 29, 2013
